Charles Habib Malik Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1930-1982 (Box 98-198)
  - Charles Habib Malik Educational Fund
    - Financial records, 1959-1968
    - Minutes and official documents, 1960-1966
  - Chautauqua Institution, Chautauqua, N.Y., 1961, 1968-1969 (Box 137)
  - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, Chicago, Ill., 1950-1959
  - Chicago Theological Seminary, Chicago, Ill., 1953, 1960-1962
  - China lobby, 1949-1951
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1952-1955
  - Christianity Today, 1956-1970
  - Claremont College, Claremont, Calif., 1961-1963
  - Coca-Cola Co., 1966-1977, undated
  - Colonial Williamsburg, Williamsburg, Va., 1960-1961, 1971-1980 (Box 138)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1947-1958, undated
  - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
    - Bicentennial events, 1953-1954
    - General correspondence, 1947-1968
    - Journals, 1950-1970, undated
  - Commission of the Churches on International Affairs See also Containers 193-195, World Council of Churches
    - 1948, Oct.-1952, Sept., (2 folders)
    - 1952, Oct.-1967, July, undated, (5 folders) (Box 139)
  - Communism, 1949-1954, undated (Box 140)
  - Conference for the Conclusion and Signature of the Treaty of Peace with Japan, San Francisco, Calif., 1951
  - Congregational Christian churches, 1953-1954, 1961
  - Congress of Flemish Economists on Development Aid, Ghent, Belgium, 1966-1968
  - Cooperative Forum, Washington, D.C., 1950-1953, undated
  - Corning Glass Works Conference, Corning, N.Y., 1960-1962
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., 1961-1981, undated
  - Council for Religion in Independent Schools, 1961-1966
  - Cuba, 1946, 1955-1957
  - Cyprus, 1950-1957, undated
  - Czechoslovakia, 1958
  - "C-Chu" miscellaneous, 1945-1982, undated, (6 folders) (Box 141)
  - "Cio-Cur" miscellaneous, 1949-1979, undated, (6 folders) (Box 142)
  - Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H., 1950-1963, 1969-1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 143)
  - DePauw University, Greencastle, Ind., 1954, 1963-1971
  - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Auswärtige Politik, Bonn, Germany, 1981-1982
  - Dominican Republic, 1947
  - "Da-De" miscellaneous, 1952-1987, undated, (2 folders)
  - "Di-Dy" miscellaneous, 1952-1975, undated (Box 144)
  - Economic Club of Detroit, Detroit, Mich., 1952-1953
  - Ecumenical Youth and Student Conference of the Middle East, Brummana, Lebanon, 1964
  - Edward Teller Center for Science, Technology and Political Thought, Boulder, Colo., 1966-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - Encyclopædia Britannica, 1962-1973
  - "E" miscellaneous, 1945-1979, undated, (2 folders)
  - First National Bank of Chicago, 1963-1965 (Box 145)
  - Ford Foundation, 1951-1973
  - Fordham University, New York, N.Y., 1951-1968
  - Foreign Affairs, 1951-1975, undated
  - Foundation for Christian Living, 1970-1973
  - France, 1957-1958
  - Front of Freedom and Man in Lebanon, 1975-1980, undated See also Oversize
    - 1975, Jan.-1977, Jan., (3 folders)
    - 1977, Feb.-1980, Dec., undated, (3 folders) (Box 146)
  - "F" miscellaneous, 1945-1978, undated, (3 folders)
  - General Electric Forum, 1961-1963 (Box 147)
  - Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1952-1979, undated
  - Germany, embassy and cultural center, Beirut, Lebanon, 1966-1973
  - Great Britian, embassy, Beirut, Lebanon, 1945, 1956-1973, undated
  - "G" miscellaneous, 1946-1981, undated, (4 folders)
  - Hague Academy of International Law, Hague, Netherlands, 1952-1953
  - Hammarskjöld, Dag, Markings, annotated by Malik, 1964-1966 (Box 148)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1952-1972
  - Harvard Club of Lebanon and Syria, Beirut, Lebanon, 1938-1941, 1962-1972
  - Harvard Club of New York City, New York, N.Y., 1946-1982, undated, (3 folders)
  - Harvard Club of Washington, Washington, D.C., 1946-1962
  - Harvard Cooperative Society, 1946-1970
  - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Ballots for Board of Overseers and Alumni Association, 1964-1973
    - General correspondence, 1949-1979, (4 folders) (Box 149)
    - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1958-1966, 1979
    - Harvard Foundation for Advanced Study and Research and honorary law degree, 1953
    - Library, 1976
    - Philosophy Department, visiting committee, 1956-1963 (Box 150)
    - Summer School of Arts and Sciences and Education
      - Classes taught by Malik, 1960, (2 folders)
      - Near East Conference, 1950-1951
      - Visiting committee, 1953-1955, (2 folders)
  - Hocking, William Ernest, festschrift, 1964-1967
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford, Calif., 1963-1980
  - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1950-1955 (Box 151)
  - Howard Payne College, Brownwood, Tex., 1960-1975
  - "H" miscellaneous, 1948-1978, undated, (5 folders)
  - Institut International de Sociologie, Seventeenth Congress, Beirut, Lebanon, 1956-1959, (3 folders) (Box 152)
  - Institute of Higher Education, Nashville, Tenn., 1960-1961
  - Institute of International Education, New York, N.Y., 1956, 1976
  - Institute on Man and Science, Problems and Prospects of the Mediterranean Seminar, Tunis, Tunisia, 1965-1967
  - Instituto de Estudios Superiores de la Empresa, Universidad de Navarra, Barcelona, Spain, 1965-1968
  - International College, Beirut, Lebanon, 1963-1974
  - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, 1976-1980, undated
  - International Council for Christian Leadership, 1954-1968, (3 folders) (Box 153)
  - International Industrial Conference, San Francisco, Calif., 1964-1969
  - International League for the Rights of Man, 1949-1973
  - International Leprosy Federation, 1967-1969
  - International Management Congress, New York, N.Y., 1962-1965
  - International NGO Conference on Human Rights, Paris, France, 1968, (2 folders)
  - International Public Relations Convention, Beirut, Lebanon, 1971 (Box 154)
  - International Theory Round Table, Washington, D.C., 1961
  - Iraq, 1948-1967, undated
  - "Ili-International R" miscellaneous, 1948-1982, undated, (5 folders)
  - "International S-Iti" miscellaneous, 1953-1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 155)
  - Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies, Baltimore, Md.
    - Miscellany, 1951-1961
    - Status of European Integration Conference, 1956-1957
    - Tensions in the Middle East Conference, 1957-1958, (2 folders)
  - Johnson Foundation, 1964-1968, undated
  - Joint Committee on Society, Development, and Peace, 1969-1970
  - Jordan, 1954, 1964-1967 (Box 156)
  - Journal of Philosophy, 1948
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1946-1978, undated, (3 folders)
  - Knights of Malta, 1961-1970, undated
  - "K" miscellaneous, 1951-1977, undated, (2 folders)
  - Laubach Literacy Fund, 1952, 1960-1981
  - League of Arab States
    - Correspondence and related material, 1947-1958
    - "Palestinian Question," manuscript by members of the league, 1946, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 157)
  - Lebanese Academy, 1971-1975, undated
  - Lebanese-American clubs and organizations, 1945-1981, undated See also names of individual clubs and organizations, (3 folders)
  - Lebanese government
    - Congratulatory messages to Lebanese officials, 1968-1970
    - Embassy, Washington, D.C.
      - Cables
        - Diplomatic, 1945-1955, undated, (2 folders)
        - Miscellaneous, 1949-1955
      - Correspondence and reports, 1945-1958, undated, (3 folders) (Box 158)
      - Office memoranda, 1945-1960, undated, (3 folders)
    - Invitations, 1962-1968, undated
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
      - Council of Ministers
        - Correspondence, 1956-1958, (2 folders)
        - Minutes, 1958, (4 folders) (Box 159)
      - Departments and offices
        - Director general, 1956-1958
        - Economic affairs, 1951-1958
        - Political affairs, 1956-1958
        - Press, 1956-1958, undated, (2 folders)
      - Financial accounts, 1957-1958, undated
      - Foreign countries
        - Congratulatory messages sent by Malik, 1958
        - United States
          - Aid programs, 1956-1958
          - American embassy, Beirut, Lebanon See Container 182, same heading
        - Visits from foreign officials, 1957-1958, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1956-1958, 1971-1974 (Box 160)
      - Other government ministries, 1956-1958, (2 folders)
      - Overseas legations and consulates, 1955-1958, undated, (2 folders)
      - Parliament
        - Foreign Affairs Committee, 1943, 1957-1958, undated
        - General correspondence, 1947-1960, undated, (3 folders)
      - Printed documents, 1957-1958
      - Souvenirs assembled by Malik (Box 161)
        - Correspondence and notes, circa 1957-1958, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1957-1958, undated
      - Telegrams and letters from public re foreign policy issues, 1957-1958, undated, (2 folders)
      - United Nations Security Council
        - Official cables
          - 1958, May-June, (5 folders)
          - 1958, July-Aug., undated, (3 folders) (Box 162)
        - Statements and resolutions, 1958
    - Ministry of National Education and Fine Arts, 1955-1957, undated, (2 folders)
    - Official governmental statements, 1956-1958, undated, (3 folders)
  - Lebanese government (Box 163)
    - Parliament
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1947-1958, undated See Container 160, General correspondence, 1947-1958, undated
        - Al-Koura district, 1957-1959, undated, (3 folders)
      - Election
        - Campaign, 1957, (2 folders)
        - Congratulatory messages, 1957, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1959-1960
  - Lebanese Information and Research Center, Washington, D.C., 1977-1982, undated, (2 folders) (Box 164)
  - "Lebanese matters," 1946-1969, undated
  - Lebanon during the interwar years, unidentified manuscript, undated, (2 folders)
  - Library of Congress
    - Alfred North Whitehead tribute, 1948
    - General correspondence, 1953
    - Gift of papers, 1976-1978
  - Life magazine See Container 180, Time and Life magazines
  - Liturgical Conference, Kansas City, Mo., 1966-1967
  - Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce and Los Angeles World Affairs Council, Los Angeles, Calif., 1958-1959
  - "L" miscellaneous, 1948-1980, undated, (4 folders) (Box 165)
  - Macmillan Co., 1951-1961
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass., Conference on Scientific Engineering Education, 1960-1961, (2 folders)
  - McGraw-Hill Publishing Co., 1964-1970, undated (Box 166)
  - "Mediterranean Dialogues" conference, Panteios School of Political Sciences, Athens, Greece, 1964
  - Methodist churches, 1954-1962
  - Mexican trip, 1960
  - Michigan State University, East Lansing, Mich., 1951-1974
  - Moore County, Tenn., 1969-1975
  - Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass., 1948-1960
  - "M-Mas" miscellaneous, 1948-1981, (2 folders)
  - "McC-Mut" miscellaneous, 1945-1979, (4 folders) (Box 167)
  - Al-Nahar magazine, 1964-1974
  - National Broadcasting Co., 1951-1959, undated
  - National Catholic Educational Association, 1961-1970
  - National Conference on Higher Education, Chicago, Ill., 1953-1954 (Box 168)
  - National Conference on International Economic and Social Development, Washington, D.C., 1952
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1949-1970, (2 folders)
  - National Farm Institute meeting, Des Moines, Iowa, 1950-1951
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1966-1969
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1971-1975
  - National War College, Washington, D.C., 1954-1964
  - Near East College Association, 1946-1959, undated
  - Near East School of Theology, Beirut, Lebanon, 1963-1973 (Box 169)
  - New England Council, 1950, undated
  - New York Herald Tribune
    - Forum, "Mobilizing America's Strength for World Security," 1950-1951
    - Miscellany, 1946-1958
  - New York Times, 1950-1981
  - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y., Lebanese pavilion, 1939, (2 folders)
  - "N-National I" miscellaneous, 1949-1974, (3 folders)
  - "National L-Nya" miscellaneous, 1933-1981, (4 folders) (Box 170)
  - "Odd" letters
    - 1951-1959, (3 folders)
    - 1960-1972, (2 folders) (Box 171)
  - Orthodox churches
    - General correspondence, 1945-1982, undated
    - Research on the Middle East, 1965, (2 folders)
  - Oxford Group
    - 1933-1934
    - 1934-1938, undated, (3 folders) (Box 172)
  - "O" miscellaneous, 1949-1974, undated, (4 folders)
  - Pakistan, 1947-1973, undated
  - Palais de la Culture, Rabiya, Lebanon, 1977 (Box 173)
  - Paul VI, Pope, 1964-1974, (2 folders)
  - Philadelphia Bulletin Forum, Philadelphia, Pa., 1950-1953
  - Presbyterian churches, 1945-1963, 1979-1982, undated, (2 folders)
  - Presbyterian Life, 1950-1969
  - Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J., 1948-1956 (Box 174)
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
    - General correspondence, 1945-1955, 1964-1981, (2 folders)
    - Near East program and conferences, 1946-1956, (2 folders)
    - Student Christian Association, 1952-1953
  - Principia College, Elsah, Ill., 1953
  - Public Relations World Congress, Montreal, Quebec, Canada, 1963-1965
  - "Pa-Pe" miscellaneous, 1946-1970, (2 folders)
  - "Ph-Pu" miscellaneous, 1949-1980, (3 folders) (Box 175)
  - Al-Qalamal-Jadid, 1953
  - Quaker Oats management meeting, Oakbrook, Ill., 1971-1972
  - Reader's Digest, 1948-1979
  - Red Cross, 1971-1975, undated
  - Religion in the Middle East, 1963-1969
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1970 (Box 176)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor See also Container 39, same heading
    - Diamond jubilee dinner, 1959
    - Nobel Peace Prize nomination, 1964-1965
  - Rotary clubs, 1948-1980
  - "R" miscellaneous, 1946-1982, undated, (3 folders)
  - Saint Maron's Feast Day celebrations, Cleveland, Ohio, 1961-1962, 1973-1974
  - Saint Sophia Greek Orthodox Church, Washington, D.C., lecture series, 1962
  - Saudi Arabia, 1957, 1966, undated (Box 177)
  - Second National Conference of Southern Baptist Men, Memphis, Tenn., 1961, (2 folders)
  - Security Storage, Washington, D.C., 1948-1949
  - Simpson College, Indianola, Iowa, 1953-1958
  - Society Ahl Al-Qalam, 1955-1956, undated
  - Society of Friends, 1948-1957, 1975
  - South African visit, 1972-1974, undated
  - Southern Federation of Syrian Lebanon American Clubs, 1954, 1963-1968 (Box 178)
  - Stanford University, Stanford, Calif., 1949-1972, (2 folders)
  - State University of New York, Rochester, N.Y., 1951-1952
  - Sudan, 1950-1958, undated
  - Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y., 1952-1956, 1973-1976, undated
  - Syrian government, undated
  - "Sac-Saint N" miscellaneous, 1947-1975, (2 folders)
  - "Saint O-Spr" miscellaneous, 1947-1975, (6 folders) (Box 179)
  - "Sta-Syr" miscellaneous, 1951-1975, undated (Box 180)
  - Television and radio, 1947-1961, 1976-1978, undated, (2 folders)
  - Texas, 1975
  - Time and Life magazines, 1949-1979, (3 folders)
  - Tunisia, 1957, undated
  - Turkey, 1957, 1966
  - "T-Thi" miscellaneous, 1950-1981, undated
  - "Tho-Ton" miscellaneous, 1949-1982, (3 folders) (Box 181)
  - Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y., 1948-1967, undated, (3 folders)
  - United Arab Republic, 1958 (Box 182)
  - United Bible Societies, 1966-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - United States government
    - American embassy, Beirut, Lebanon, 1944, 1956-1979, (2 folders)
    - Congressional correspondence, 1945-1982, undated
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1961-1967, undated See also Container 249, Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization (Box 183)
    - Miscellany, 1951-1976, undated
    - National Prayer Breakfast, 1967-1982, (2 folders)
    - Official statements re Middle East and Lebanon, circa 1956-circa 1958, (3 folders)
    - Point IV technical and economic assistance to Lebanon, 1950-1957, undated, (3 folders) (Box 184)
    - Presidential inauguration, 1952-1953
    - White House, 1955-1969, 1977-1981, undated
  - Universität Freiburg, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany, 1957-1958
  - Université Saint Joseph, Beirut, Lebanon, 1943-1967, undated
  - University Christian Center, Beirut, Lebanon, 1959-1970
  - University of California, Berkeley and Los Angeles, Calif., 1954-1960, 1980
  - University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1950-1965 (Box 185)
  - University of Denver, Denver, Colo., 1949-1962
  - University of Dubuque, Dubuque, Iowa, 1951-1956, 1979-1980
  - University of New Hampshire, Durham, N.H., 1963-1965
  - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, N.C., 1959-1965, 1972
  - University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Ind., 1952-1982, undated, (2 folders)
  - University of Oregon, Eugene, Oreg., 1950
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1949-1982, undated, (8 folders) (Box 186)
  - Venezuela, 1947, 1974 (Box 187)
  - Virginia State Bar Association, 1962-1963
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1952-1974, undated
  - Washington Cathedral, Washington, D.C., 1945-1962, undated
  - Washington University, St. Louis, Mo., 1951-1966
  - Wedgwood Society of New York, New York, N.Y., 1959-1972
  - Westinghouse Electric Corp.
    - Developing Nations Advisory Committee
      - 1967-1970, (3 folders)
      - 1971-1974, (4 folders) (Box 188)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 189)
    - Middle East representative, 1954-1955
    - New York World's Fair, New York, N.Y., time capsule, 1964, (2 folders)
  - Westminster College, Fulton, Mo., 1952-1969, undated
  - Wheaton College, Wheaton, Ill., 1947-1982
  - Wide World Lecture Bureau
    - 1962-1964, (2 folders)
    - 1965-1973, (2 folders) (Box 190)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1961-1963, (2 folders)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1973
  - World Assembly for Human Rights, Montreal, Canada, 1967-1968
  - World Center for Liturgical Studies, Boca Raton, Fla., 1963-1974
  - World Convention on Christian Education, Toronto, Canada, 1949-1951
  - World Council of Christian Education (Box 191)
    - 1948-1968, (7 folders)
    - 1969-1973, (6 folders) (Box 192)
  - World Council of Churches See also Containers 138-139, Commission of the Churches on International Affairs (Box 193)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1973, undated, (5 folders)
    - Minutes, programs, circulars, speeches, and writings
      - 1948-1951, (2 folders)
      - 1952-1955, (4 folders) (Box 194)
      - 1955-1974, undated, (6 folders) (Box 195)
  - World Economic Progress Assembly and Exposition, Chicago, Ill., 1961-1962 (Box 196)
  - World Lebanese Cultural Union, 1965-1981, undated, (2 folders)
  - "W-Wi" miscellaneous, 1946-1979, undated, (3 folders)
  - "Wo" miscellaneous, 1948-1982, undated, (3 folders) (Box 197)
  - Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1967-1968
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn., 1947-1964
  - Young Men's Christian Association
    - Cairo, Egypt, 1930-1932, undated
    - General correspondence, 1946-1964, 1972, (2 folders)
  - Young Women's Christian Association, 1946-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 198)
  - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, 1955-1979, undated
- Speeches, 1928-1982 (Box 198-231)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches, correspondence, and lists.
  Arranged by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Engagements cancelled, 1948-1958, (4 folders) (Box 198)
  - Engagements declined
    - 1949-1950, (3 folders)
    - 1951, (7 folders) (Box 199)
    - 1952 (Box 200)
      - A-N, (8 folders)
      - O-Z, (4 folders) (Box 201)
    - 1953
      - A-I, (3 folders)
      - J-Z, (3 folders) (Box 202)
    - 1954, (4 folders)
    - 1955-1957, (6 folders) (Box 203)
    - 1958
      - A-C
      - D-Y, (2 folders) (Box 204)
    - 1959
      - A-C, (3 folders)
      - D-U, (6 folders) (Box 205)
      - V-Y (Box 206)
    - 1961, (5 folders)
    - 1962 (Box 207)
  - Lists
    - Chronological, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1951, undated
    - Topical, undated
  - Texts
    - 1928, Feb. 9-1940, Apr. 27, (5 folders)
    - 1940, Apr. 29-1946, Oct. 3, (7 folders) (Box 208)
    - 1946, Nov. 9-1948, Aug. 29, (7 folders) (Box 209)
    - 1948, Sept. 15-1949, Nov. 25, (6 folders) (Box 210)
    - 1949, Nov. 26-1950, June 27, (7 folders) (Box 211)
    - 1950, July 9-1951, Feb. 19, (5 folders) (Box 212)
    - 1951, Mar. 4-1952, Aug. 17, (6 folders) (Box 213)
    - 1952, Oct. 10-1953, Sept. 28, (5 folders) (Box 214)
    - 1953, Oct. 11-1954, Dec. 13, (6 folders) (Box 215)
    - 1955, Feb. 3-1956, June 28, (6 folders) (Box 216)
    - 1956, June 29-1957, Dec. 21, (6 folders) (Box 217)
    - 1958, Jan. 23-1959, Jan. 31, (6 folders) (Box 218)
    - 1959, Feb. 4-1959, Dec. 7, (6 folders) (Box 219)
    - 1960, Feb. 13-June 11, (5 folders) (Box 220)
    - 1960, June 13-1961, July 26, (5 folders) (Box 221)
    - 1961, Aug. 12-1962, Nov. 19, (6 folders) (Box 222)
    - 1963, Feb. 17-1965, June 16, (6 folders) (Box 223)
    - 1965, Sept. 13-1967, Aug. 24, (5 folders) (Box 224)
    - 1967, Sept. 13-1969, Dec. 11, (6 folders) (Box 225)
    - 1970, Jan. 2-1972, Mar. 23, (5 folders) (Box 226)
    - 1972, May 17-1974, Oct. 7, (6 folders) (Box 227)
    - 1974, Nov. 5-1978, Nov. 20, (7 folders) (Box 228)
    - 1979, Jan. 18-1981, Oct. 8, (7 folders) (Box 229)
    - 1981, Oct. 26-1982, Apr. 28, (2 folders) (Box 230)
    - Undated
      - In Arabic, (4 folders)
      - In English re (Box 231)
        - International affairs
        - Philosophical and religious issues
        - United Nations
- Writings, 1930-1994 (Box 231-249)
  Drafts of articles, book reviews, books, introductions, forewords, and prefaces, correspondence, and printed matter.
  Arranged by type of publication. Drafts of articles, book reviews, introductions, prefaces, and forewords are arranged chronologically therein; books are arranged alphabetically by title or subject and chronologically therein.
  - Articles (Box 231)
    - 1930-1948, (3 folders)
    - 1949-1954, (6 folders) (Box 232)
    - 1955-1965, (6 folders) (Box 233)
    - 1966-1976, (6 folders) (Box 234)
    - 1977-1986, 1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 235)
  - Book reviews by Malik, 1935, 1952-1969, undated
  - Books
    - Alā durūb al-dīmugrātīyah, 1977
    - "The Challenge of East and West," undated, (3 folders); (6 folders) (Box 236)
    - Christ and Crisis
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1961-1969
      - Drafts, 1962 (Box 237)
    - Complete works of Malik in Arabic project, undated
      - Introduction, (6 folders)
      - "On Lebanon", (3 folders) (Box 238)
      - "On Philosophy", (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 239)
      - "On Scientific Research in the Present Era"
    - Complete works of Malik in English project, proposal, 1967
    - "Diplomacy," undated
      - Bibliography
      - Drafts, (2 folders)
    - God and Man in Contemporary Christian Thought, 1967-1972 See also Containers 107-108, Symposia on "God and Man in Contemporary Religious Thought"
    - God and Man in Contemporary Islamic Thought, 1971-1973 See also Containers 107-108, Symposia on "God and Man in Contemporary Religious Thought", (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 240)
    - Li-mādhā agra' al-kitāb al-mugaddas, 1973
    - Li-mādhā ūmin, 1966
    - Li-mādhā ūmin bi-yasū' al-masīh, undated
    - Lubān īdhātih, 1973
    - Man in the Struggle for Peace
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966, 1979
      - Drafts, 1963, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 241)
    - "A Message to the Businessman," undated, (3 folders)
    - Philosophical work by Malik in Arabic, undated, (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box 242, Box 243)
    - [Title withheld] See Closed, (3 folders)
    - "The Race," undated, (1 folder) (Box 244)
    - Readings in Philosophy, 1939-1940, (3 folders)
    - Shārl Mālik wa-al-qudiyah al-filastīnīyah, 1973 (Box 245)
    - "The System of Whitehead's Metaphysics," 1937, (3 folders)
    - War and Peace
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1949-1952, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 246)
        - Publisher, 1950-1952, undated
      - Final text, 1950
      - Miscellaneous drafts, 1949
    - The Wonder of Being
      - Correspondence, 1970-1975
      - Drafts, 1969-1974, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 247)
      - Miscellany, 1974, undated
  - Introductions, forewords, and prefaces, 1956-1974
  - Thesis See Containers 254-257, same heading
  - Unidentified
    - Arabic drafts, undated